alfa.com.lb 2019-12-22

# Alfa | Lebanon's first mobile network managed by Orascom Telecom | About - Privacy Policy

**Alfa Privacy Policy**

We are glad to have you at Alfa; earning and maintaining your trust matters to us.  
Nowadays, with the rapidly and ever-increasing complexity and reach of technology, protection and proper use of personal information is becoming paramount.  
Alfa promises to be transparent with you about all practices and measures deployed to protect your privacy.  
The Privacy Policy in hand, together with the respective terms and conditions of the services you have subscribed to, explains what personal information we are collecting, when we collect it, how do we keep it secure and in which circumstances we share it.

**What Personal information do we collect?**  
From your signed contract: Name, Gender, Date of Birth, Identity Document number, email address, Billing addresses, Telephone number, Fax number, Banking information  
Your traffic data related information, cost of your communications, your device details and phone usage, your approximate location, and your browsing history  
All communications between the customer and Alfa call center  
Any other information required to activate a service

**When do we collect your personal information?**  
We can get your personal information when you:  
Buy a product or service from us (including buying online, over the phone and in any Alfa store or point of service)  
Register for a specific product or service (such as registering your name and address details for a service or bundle)  
Contact us for a support, assistance, clarification or complaint  
Submit feedback on our surveys  
Use our network  
Visit or browse our website

**Why do we collect personal information?**  
To validate you as a registered customer when using our services  
To manage your account with us and for billing purposes  
To bill you for using our products or services  
To be able to assist you and respond to any questions or concerns you may have about using our network, products or services  
To carry out research and statistical analysis, respond to your needs, which leads to new or improved products and services. So, we will be able to contact you with offers or promotions based on how you use our products and services  
To manage our network and help us design and optimize it such as managing the volume of calls, texts, internet data, etc ...  
To allow us to recommend/customize products and services targeting your specific personal needs and preferences for a better customer experience  
To meet our legal, regulatory and law enforcement agencies’ requirements  
To perform quality and financial control and improve the quality of experience  
To prevent and detect fraud

**In which circumstances your personal information is disclosed?**  
Acting in good faith if we believe such action is necessary to conform with a legal requirement or comply with the legal process, protect and defend the rights or property of Alfa, we may share your personal information with:  
Subsidiaries, affiliated companies, and trusted third parties (including agents, subcontractors and suppliers which are integral to providing some of our services)

A person acting as your legal representative, agent or authorized user  
Official or legal entities for the purpose of collecting unpaid due bills  
Third-parties such as financial institutions and banks to facilitate your billing payments  
Legal authorities and court when legally requested or when it is allowed and required by law  
Ministry of Telecommunications being the owner and the regulator

It is within your duty and for your own interest to provide us with accurate personal information at all times, and update us of any changes to your personal information.

Before we collect, use or disclose your Personal Information we may need your consent:  
Imply consent: obtained from your actions. For example, if you give us your address, we may use it to send you bills  
Express consent: is when you explicitly consent verbally, or by signing a document, or ticking a box or performing a similar act demonstrating your consent

In some cases, it may be impossible or inappropriate to obtain your consent such as:  
if it is clearly in your interests  
to comply with legal and law enforcement agencies’ requirements  
or to collect a debt.

We will not share your information with 3rd party organizations to contact you about their products and services without capturing your explicit, informed, and specific consent.

**Phone directory enquiries**  
Upon contract signature (unless explicitly rejection has been picked out), Alfa will include your contact details including your name or trading name, address, and mobile phone number in a directory, which will make your details available through directory enquiry services.  
If you want your contact details to be updated or withheld from directory enquiry services, please contact us.

**Websites limited liability**  
Our websites may have links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers, and affiliates, including online stores and service providers hosted within our website. Such websites have their own privacy policies and hence we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

**Cookies**  
Like many other websites, we use cookies. Cookies are small files that websites put on your device to provide you with a better, more personal and relevant online experience. Some cookies are essential for websites to work and others remember things about you to give you a better, more enjoyable online experience every time you visit the website. By continuing to use our websites, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. Alternatively, you can manage them in your browser settings. However, refusing cookies may mean that you are unable to access certain parts of our websites.  
We use various types of cookies, including essential cookies (which help you move around the secure areas of the websites and do things you have specifically come to the websites for, for examples remembering products you put in your basket and information you enter in forms), cookies for website information (which collect anonymous information about how visitors use our websites, including the most popular pages and any error pages you see), and cookies that save your settings.

**How long we retain your personal information for?**  
Some of the personal information will be retained for a reasonable period after termination of the service subscription. This period depends on the business purposes and legal requirements.

**How do we keep your personal information secure?**  
The purpose of gathering information from the customers serves the purpose of operating our business & enhancing our customers experience.  
We -Alfa- are committed to maintain, protect and respect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your personal Information. Our highly qualified employees constantly deploy state of the art systems, and apply rigorous security policies, processes and procedures to prevent the theft, loss, or unauthorized use of your personal information, in line with the international information security standards and best practices.

**Changes to our privacy policy**  
Any future changes to this Policy will be posted on Alfa website [www.alfa.com.lb](https://www.alfa.com.lb/) and shall be effective starting that date. Please check our website regularly.

**Contact us**  
For any inquiry, we are always reachable through the following communication channels:  
Call Center through 03391111  
Call Center live chat on our website [www.alfa.com.lb](https://www.alfa.com.lb/) or Alfa Mobile application  
Facebook through https://[www.facebook.com/alfatelecommunications](https://www.facebook.com/alfatelecommunications)  
by E-mail to alfa.customercareteam@alfamobile.com.lb and Fax on: 03391109, or by visiting our [stores](https://www.alfa.com.lb/en/find-a-store)
